[theme music playing]
[laughs]
[Helena] I will not allow someone
like Lily Cruz to slander me.
This Lily Cruz just did it.
[Jude] Helena Montoya,
you are under arrest
for arms trafficking
and human trafficking.
Come with us.
-Wait!
-Let go of me! Don't touch me!
[Emilia] You can't do this to my mama!
[Julio] The mother and her daughter,
both taken down by a wildflower.
Looks like you have
something planned for Lily Cruz.
I am above the law.
No, wait. I am the law.
And that Lily Cruz just declared
a full-fledged war
against Red Dragon.
[Diego] Whatever it is you're planning
to help Red Dragon escape,
I'll make sure it fails.
I know what Red Dragon is capable of.
Red Dragon's claws dig in deep,
enough so to infiltrate the NBI.
What are you hiding from me?
Why don't you just forget
about everything, Arnaldo?!
It won't do you or any of us any good!
Take this chance to start over.
Don't throw it away.
[Damian] Red Dragon's
planning something big.
-[Helena cackling]
-[gunshot]
[Diego] Lily, get ready. She's on her way.
-[gunfire]
-Hey!
[rapid gunfire]
-[tires screeching]
-[engine revving]
[chopper blades whirring]
[blades whirring]
[intense music playing]
[chopper blades whirring]
[Helena taunting]
[Helena laughing]
[gunfire]
-[Helena keeps laughing]
-[Lily grunting in frustration]
-Let's go!
-Move! Move!
[yells]
[yelling]
This isn't over, Helena!
[panting]
[Lily] What happened?!
Huh?! You just let her escape!
She's gone!
[Lily raging]
[woman on TV] Reports say
an unidentified group
helped Red Dragon escape
by whisking the syndicate leader away
aboard a helicopter.
It seems Red Dragon outsmarted
the authorities yet again.
Stay tuned for more updates
on this developing story.
This is Jerika Panganiban reporting.
Where are you going?
[tense music playing]
You are not my boss.
I don't need to report
my every move to you.
[Jude] We need to establish
the chopper's exact location.
And according to this,
it's bound to land in the Visayas.
[Noel] Okay, track it down now.
I'll trace the pickup that attacked us.
[motorcycle engine revving]
We shouldn't waste our time
looking for the pickup.
We need to find the chopper
that picked up Red Dragon.
We need to concentrate our forces.
Agent Salonga's right.
We need to find the pickup
that attacked us too.
With all due respect, Miss Cruz,
I'm not asking for your opinion.
Can you please just let us do our job?
With all due respect, agent,
wasn't I the one who tipped you off?
If you guys were competent,
I wouldn't need to interfere.
The moment I sense you're messing up,
you guys can bet I'll take
matters into my own hands.
[tense music playing]
Agent Salonga.
Get moving. I'll be in touch.
Men, let's move.
[engine noise fading]
Are there any updates
on Red Dragon's whereabouts?
Negative, Mercedes.
-And what was that?!
-[tense music playing]
Someone else messed up the operation.
They weren't police.
[Damian] A different group, Mercedes.
And what's with that look, huh?
You!
You're the only one with the motive
to sabotage the organization.
You sent the chopper for your mother
so the syndicate
would think of you as a hero.
No! What?!
This isn't a contest,
so just drop the act.
Where is Red Dragon?
Excuse me, but I thought it was
you who helped Mama escape.
You're trying to impress the syndicate
because you want
to take Mama's place, right?
You know, I was about to
applaud your chopper stunt.
That was really brilliant.
I didn't send the chopper.
Okay. If neither of us was responsible,
it could be the authorities, right?
You know, instead of just standing there,
you better go and look for her instead.
That's your job, remember?
Don't just stand there.
[tense music playing]
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Yes.
Mhm. Yes.
[Mercedes] Okay.
[pensive music playing]
Red Dragon escaped.
I was so close, but I lost her.
Diego, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, but the fight isn't over.
I'll still need your help.
[suspenseful music playing]
Okay. I'll talk to my partners
right away. Goodbye.
-Who was that?
-Is that about Mama?
The Big Four want to set a meeting.
[ominous music playing]
Huh? Big Four? And who the hell are they?
Were they the ones who helped
Red Dragon escape?
We'll find out once they get here.
So be on high alert. I will update you.
Wait. I'm asking.
Who are the Big Four?
What's your deal?
Who are they?!
The four of them each lead
Red Dragon's operations
in the north, south, east,
and west areas of the country.
You mean to say,
my mother's scope is nationwide?
Not just nationwide.
You'd be surprised if I told you how far.
[suspenseful music playing]
Wow.
[brooding music playing]
Lily, here have a drink.
The sooner I find out
who helped her escape,
the sooner I can find
where Red Dragon is hiding.
Mom, what I'm worried
about right now is Diego.
He wasn't able to escape
from the syndicate.
I'm the reason he's in there.
I should've done something…
so he can escape while he still can.
[Camia] It was Diego's decision
to help you.
Don't shoulder all of the blame for this.
Diego will get out.
And we will be together.
I swear it.
-Papa.
-Hmm?
I cannot believe this.
Mama is gone and you're not
doing anything about it.
How can you not do anything, Papa?
Have you forgotten that she's my mother?
You're not even the least bit worried.
Your mother is supposed to be a dragon.
You don't have to worry.
She won't let the police
or Lily Cruz or anybody
catch her that easily.
You know what you should do?
You should focus on your…
little organization.
[sighs]
And, by the way, I heard that there's
a vacuum of power in your group.
Why don't you grab it?
Who knows? That might be your forte.
It's not time yet, Papa.
The Big Four's still there.
They are the heads of Mama's operations
in the south, north, east,
and west of the Philippines.
They're lined up for that.
Besides, I still have other business.
Like what?
I will fumigate Mama's office,
to rid it of a bug.
A bug named Mercedes.
Good grief, Emilia. There you go again.
This is exactly your problem.
[stammering] You don't know
what to prioritize in your life
and in everything that you do.
Listen, in politics, even…
unfortunately, in syndicates
and criminal organizations,
that is a no-no. You have
to know your priorities.
That's why you, Emilia,
no matter where you find yourself…
chances are you're bound to fail.
[footsteps fading]
-Diego.
-Lily.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I put you in this situation.
And now the battle's still not over
because that wretched dragon
managed to escape.
-[breathes shakily]
-Lily, I'm there because I need to be.
I know that.
But I don't want this anymore.
You have to leave
Red Dragon's camp. Please.
I can help more from the inside,
and you know that.
I can monitor Emilia
and Mercedes' every move.
It'll be easier for us
to hunt down Red Dragon.
It might.
But, Diego, what if they catch you?
[tender music playing]
I'd rather die for a cause
than live without--
[shushes] Diego, no.
I won't allow this.
We can win this fight without
anyone getting hurt, caught,
or, most importantly, killed.
Do you understand?
So while you're still in Red Dragon's den,
nothing bad must happen to you, Diego.
Promise me that.
I promise.
I will never leave you.
[radio] An unidentified group
helped Red Dragon escape
by whisking the syndicate
leader away aboard a helicopter.
It seems Red Dragon outsmarted
the authorities yet again.
Stay tuned for more updates--
The bad news keeps piling up.
It's getting really old.
How come, those who fight
for what's right are the ones
who get deprived
of their right to be happy?
To be with their loved ones?
Diego and Lily are strong.
They can get past any challenge
they might face.
That's why you shouldn't worry
too much about them, love.
I'll help them in any way I can.
Honestly, love, we are so lucky.
Despite all the chaos here in Ardiente,
we're still together.
I'm so lucky I have you.
I'm the lucky one, love.
All right now. I have to go.
-To take Arnaldo home?
-Yes.
Anna, Jepoy, I'll do it.
I'm leaving anyway.
Arnaldo?
Arnaldo.
[ominous music playing]
Hey. He's not here.
Arnaldo?
Where did he go?
[crickets chirping]
By the way, the pickup
truck that attacked us
and helped Red Dragon escape…
I just know…
that's how we'll unmask
whoever is helping Helena.
It'll lead us to wherever she's hiding.
Diego, someone needs to go back there.
Leave it to me.
Thank you, Diego.
[dramatic music playing]
Just hang in there.
[tense music playing]
Damian, have some coffee.
Um…
Camia, I'm sorry if I have to leave.
Well, I'm in no position
to stop you from leaving.
Besides, you have your own life to live.
By the way, thanks for the tip
you gave to Lily.
Too bad Red Dragon
was still able to escape
after all that she did.
Some group helped her escape,
and it wasn't Red Dragon's.
How can you tell?
[slow tense music playing]
Well, it's just a hunch.
Red Dragon's got a lot of connections
that's why she's so elusive.
After all these years, this is
the first time she got caught.
All because of Lily.
Damian, who told you
about Red Dragon's plan?
Who gave you the tip?
Maybe that person could
help us chase her down.
No one.
I just…
I just heard it from friends
who have connections.
But they've changed for the better.
Like you?
Yes.
Damian, thank you for helping Lily,
but I hope your friends
won't be a bad influence
or prevent you from leading a decent life.
Thanks, Camia.
[tense music playing]
Is everything ready for the Big Four?
Everything's ready, Mercedes.
[Mercedes] What's the
latest update on Red Dragon?
We've retrieved the pickup
truck that rescued her.
It's been secured downstairs.
Right now, we're tracking down its owner.
Good. Keep me updated.
[suspenseful music playing]
Hmm…
Mama is such an evil genius, you know.
I have a feeling
she orchestrated her escape.
You're right.
I won't be surprised
if she planned all this out.
She's Red Dragon, after all.
So, I've decided not
to worry too much about it.
Instead, I'll just prepare everything
for the queen's return.
Well, that's not
your task to do. It's mine.
[chuckles] Red Dragon breathes fire.
You, on the other hand,
breathe nothing more than hot air.
Laugh now, Mercedes.
Laugh now all you want,
because I'll be taking over
your position soon enough…
I'm sure of that.
[laptop shuts]
You wish.
[tense music playing]
[ominous music plays]
[grunts]
Oh.
Arnaldo, my son. Where have you been?
Uh…
-I went back to the village.
-Mhm.
I was hoping I'd find something…
that would clear things up for me…
but I didn't.
And I don't know
why I keep coming back here.
That goes without saying, Arnaldo.
This is your home, after all.
You know what, Arnaldo?
[exhales]
I will help you get well.
And once you've fully recovered,
I swear you'll forget about that village
and all the people you were with.
Because roaches like them
don't have the right
to socialize with a crown prince like you.
[grunting] Drink up, my son. Drink up.
[tense music playing]
-[ice clinking]
-[whiffs]
I shouldn't.
[tense music playing]
Do you still want to track
down the pickup?
We need to find the pickup, Agent Salonga.
And I don't get why your partner
refuses to cooperate with me!
[sighs] You mean Jude?
I'll take care of it.
I'll bring my men to the scene.
You know what?
Why don't you just report him
to your superior?
Or maybe have him investigated?
You don't want to have someone
like him in your agency.
He might drag everyone down.
[slow tense music playing]
[footsteps approaching]
We've retrieved the
pickup truck that rescued her.
It's been secured downstairs.
[suspenseful music playing]
[suspenseful music intensifies]
-You're seriously suspecting me?
-[folio slaps against table]
Do you actually think
I helped Red Dragon escape?!
[chuckling] Wow! Take
it easy, Agent Asuncion.
I never said you're working for
Red Dragon. You just did!
All because I don't want
to look for that darn pickup?!
-Jude!
-And why is that?
Why are you hiding it?
Or are you covering for someone?
If I were you, Agent Salonga,
I'd be careful.
You saw how your friend reacted.
Watch your back because if
my suspicions prove true,
there's a snake among us.
[Lily] Keep me posted, Agent Salonga.
That woman's unbelievable.
She keeps meddling in our affairs.
She has no boundaries.
[tense music playing]
Okay. I'll be expecting you. Bye.
Madam Emilia, Mr. Ramon Lim of the north.
Perfect.
-[Emilia] Mr. Ramon Lim.
-Hello! Hello!
Nice to meet you. I am Emilia.
-[Ramon] Emilia.
-[Emilia] Have a seat, please.
Hold on.
I thought all four of us would be here.
Where are the others? Why is it just us?
Relax, Mr. Ramon Lim of the north.
Oscar Evangelista, Carlos Isidro,
and Salvador Victoria
will be arriving in a short while,
so, in the meantime,
please make yourself comfortable
and let us bond.
I wanna get to know you, Mr. Lim.
Have a seat, please.
Mr. Lim.
Oh, Mercedes! Mercedes, how are you?
[Mercedes] I'm good.
It's good to see you, sir.
[Ramon] You look very nice!
-Thank you very much. So do you.
-You look very good.
Okay.
Enough with the pleasantries.
This isn't a reunion.
We're here to talk about
Red Dragon's disappearance,
and whether you had anything
to do with it, Mr. Lim.
False alarm! False alarm!
I don't know anything about that.
Why don't you ask
the others coming? Not me.
[tense music playing]
Don't tell me you believe that Lily Cruz?
I asked our men to look for the pickup.
That's the only way
we can prove your innocence.
I need to go.
Where are you going?
Jude, you need to answer
those allegations.
Stop right there, Agent Jude Asuncion.
The pickup that attacked us
while Red Dragon was escaping
is registered under
one of your businesses.
[tense music playing]
We've retrieved the pickup truck
that rescued her.
It's been secured downstairs.
Boss, we found the owner of the plate.
Thank you, boss.
-Good afternoon, sir.
-Hi.
Sir, these are the packages
you can choose from.
When are you planning
to hold your seminar?
Our management is still deciding on it.
-Hmm.
-This is a nice place.
-It is.
-Who owns it?
The Asuncions.
Mrs. Connie Asuncion manages the business.
Would you like some coffee, sir?
-Sure.
-Hold on. I'll bring you a cup.
[suspenseful music playing]
Does the name Connie Asuncion ring a bell?
It should.
Because I found out your mother
owns an events company.
An events company that owns
a particular pickup truck.
Are you still insisting
that you're innocent?
[suspenseful music continues]
You helped Red Dragon escape.
[suspenseful music intensifies]
[tense music playing]
-Jude!
-Hey!
[women screaming]
-Asuncion--
-Jude!
Asuncion!
[cocks gun]
Jude!
My gun!
-Men, go after him!
-Yes, sir!
[cocks gun]
[gunshots]
[grunting]
[tense music playing]
[consecutive gunshots]
[triumphant music playing]
You aren't going to hell
just yet, Asuncion.
You still have a lot of explaining to do.
-Men, arrest him.
-Yes, sir.
[tense music intensifies]
So… Any more visitors?
Or as usual, are you just
sitting on your hands?
You might be Red Dragon's daughter,
but I'm the one the Big Four recognizes.
Still think you can win?
[scoffs]
[footsteps approaching]
Madam, Oscar Evangelista of the south.
Oscar Evangelista, godfather of the south.
Emilia.
[giggles] Nice to finally meet you, Oscar.
Thank you for your time.
Have a seat, please.
Can I offer you anything? Scotch? Wine?
Maybe later. I'm with someone.
Oh. All right. [exhales]
Here she is.
Well… Hello, ladies.
[Oscar] Yeah. This is Natalie.
I know her.
-[chuckles]
-[stammers] So, you are…
[Emilia laughs] Oh!
[Natalie] Yes, we're together.
We are a pair.
You look shocked, Emilia.
I told you, didn't I?
I'll do whatever it takes to get in.
-[giggles]
-So, what did it take?
-Spreading your legs?
-[both laugh]
No. I just bent over.
That easy. [chuckles]
And because of my lovey-dovey,
I am now the queen
of the syndicate in the south,
while you two…
are fighting over your mother's leftovers.
[chuckles] And right now,
I'm so thrilled to be here.
I can't wait to hear how you're
going to convince my lovey-dovey
to get on your side.
[mouthing] Lovey-dovey.
[chuckles] And I'm so excited
to make you eat your words.
[huffs] Have a seat, please.
Gladly.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia huffing]
Sit!
This won't take long, Agent Asuncion.
We're just going to ask you
where your boss is hiding.
-Where is Red Dragon?!
-I don't know!
[tense music playing]
Agent Salonga, aren't you
going to do anything?
You know what to do
to make someone talk, right?
You don't know where Red Dragon is?
I said I don't! [grunts]
[Jude sputtering]
[coughs]
Let's do this the easy way…
unless you want to do it the hard way.
You work for Red Dragon, right?
Are you part of the group
that helped Red Dragon escape?
[breathes deeply]
Jude, just admit it!
We're trying to help you!
No matter how much you hurt me…
you won't get anything
because I'm telling the truth!
I am not part of Red Dragon's syndicate!
You're telling the truth?
You're telling the truth?!
Look into my eyes
and tell me that you are--
-Yes!
-[slaps, thuds]
[tense music playing]
[Emilia] Carlos Isidro of the west,
Silverio Victoria of the east,
Ramon Lim of the north,
Oscar Evangelista of the south,
we are complete.
So, since it's clear
to all of us that none of you
helped my mother escape, not Mercedes…
Certainly, not me.
[hat slaps against table]
If you didn't help Red Dragon escape,
or you, or you, or me, then who did?!
It's possible that it's one
of Madam's connections
that we have yet to meet.
And only Mama can answer
your questions right now.
You know, I think we should
move on with this discussion.
Shouldn't we be talking about
who's going to replace
Red Dragon while she's gone?
[clears throat] Oscar,
it's quite obvious that I
should take Red Dragon's place,
since I'm her only daughter.
Why should we do that?
Did she contact you?
Why don't we have an election?
Emilia versus me
for Red Dragon's position.
I agree. That sounds so interesting.
Who will inherit the wings
and the scales of Red Dragon?
[Natalie] Hmm…
Is it the high and mighty daughter?
Or is it the fire-breathing protégé?
I wonder… I'm going to watch this.
[tense music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Lily] Agent Asuncion
doesn't want to talk.
He says he doesn't work for Red Dragon.
I'll find out if he's telling the truth.
Thank you.
[phone locks]
I have a bad feeling about this, Lily.
It's impossible that Jude
is working for Red Dragon.
I know he's your friend,
but don't let that blind you.
The people you trust
can be the same people
who'll stab you in the back
when you least expect them to.
So open your eyes, Noel.
[suspenseful music playing]
[papers shuffling]
-Is this it?
-Yes, ma'am.
[slow tense music playing]
[scoffs]
Fifty million?
Wake your friend up.
Jude. Jude. Jude.
[gasps]
Agent Jude Asuncion!
Well, you're right.
Someone told me
that it is impossible
that you work for Red Dragon.
[scoffing] Then what are you waiting for?
Untie me now!
[ominous music playing]
Then again, I'm not stupid.
[Lily] I don't believe things that easily.
If you're not with Red Dragon,
then you work for another group
that helped her escape.
Don't you?
Don't you?!
I got your bank account records.
Looks like you're a wealthy man,
Jude Asuncion.
You received fifty million pesos
just to help her escape.
Now tell me…
Who do you really work for?
Who is your boss?
[stammers] No matter what you do…
you can't stop Red Dragon…
because she's already left the country.
Red Dragon left the Philippines?
To go where?
Where is Red Dragon?!
Tell me!
Where?!
I'm not the one you should be torturing!
[Lily] Then who?!
I served 10 years in this job! [quivers]
I just did this to earn money
for my child!
You know that, Noel! You know that!
There are people out there worse than me!
Go after them, not me!
I'm not a bad person!
But you still helped a big-time
crime lord escape.
As the saying goes,
"Regrets always come in the end."
Do you know what will happen to you now?
You will be imprisoned.
Your reputation will be ruined.
And the money that you received?
It will rot just like you will.
But if you'll confess, I'll help you out.
[Lily] Your friend and I will help you.
Jude Asuncion,
will you cooperate with us?
You won't be able to help me.
Because you don't know what I need!
-That's not--
-Jude! Jude, stop!
Jude! Jude!
[gunshot]
[grunting]
[Jude sputtering]
[dramatic music playing]
[Jude coughing]
[sobs]
[Jude gasping]
[brooding music playing]
[door opening]
Jude is now in the hospital.
I'm sorry.
How is he?
He's in critical condition.
But don't worry. The minute he wakes up,
I won't stop interrogating him
until I get the truth.
Thank you.
No matter which country you hide in…
I'll find you, Red Dragon.
Justice will be served…
I'll free Diego from your clutches.
[suspenseful music playing]
[man speaking Chinese] Boss, your phone.
[Helena speaking Chinese] Thank you.
[charged music playing]
Ha! An election?
Pack your bags, Emilia.
You're going to lose.
Well, thank you, Papa,
for your astounding support.
I really appreciate it.
Come on! I'm not trying
to piss you off, okay?
I'm just telling you the truth.
If they decide to vote on it,
you'll surely lose, because two
members of the Big Four…
who you've talked to will
definitely vote for Mercedes.
Now, the third one, he couldn't care less.
He doesn't care who wins,
as long as he's still there.
The fourth one…
Since the two men have already
voted for Mercedes, he wouldn't
waste his vote on you.
He might as well join the other
two by voting for Mercedes.
So, you see? You'll lose.
You're really happy
seeing me like this, huh?
No, I'm just telling you the truth.
You and I, we're the same.
We have this insatiable hunger for power.
We're never satisfied.
We want to keep acquiring
more… more power.
-So, you see, we're the same.
-No, Papa.
I beg to disagree. We're not the same
because although you've already
acquired power as governor,
you still love seeing the people
around you living in misery.
You know what I think, Papa?
You're not power hungry…
you're just simply evil.
Ouch. That hurts.
Come on.
I am not evil.
I just know how to look out
for number one.
When everything goes up in
flames and the smoke clears,
you will see that I'm still on top.
You know why? All my life,
I've taken care of three people.
Three people who make sure that
I will always remain on top.
You know who they are?
I, me, and myself.
-[Julio laughing hysterically]
-[huffs]
Well, enjoy your lunch.
Enjoy.
I'm leaving you. Ah…
I will be in my room…
wallowing in victory.
[Julio laughing]
[Julio humming]
[Julio] King!
[phone ringing]
Hello?
Baby girl?
Mama, where are you?
High up, overlooking a fabulous city.
I called because I have
something important to tell you.
While Mama Dragon is away,
I want my baby dragon to slay.
Baby dragon? What are you talking about?
It's time for you to test
your wings and prepare to fly.
Since you're a dragon's daughter,
I want you to learn…
how to breathe fire while I'm away.
Yes, my baby dragon.
You're going to be
the organization's leader.
And I want you to burn them all.
[chuckles]
Me?! You want me to…
-take your place, Mama?
-But of course, baby girl.
So, please. Make your Mama dragon proud.
Of course.
[Emilia] Um, Mama…
Who helped you escape
and when are you coming back?
All you need to know right now
is that I'm having a golden moment
in a fantastic city.
And don't worry about me, okay?
Mm…
Okay. Um, Mama?
Yes, baby girl?
I just wanna thank you
for believing in me.
I thought you didn't believe in me
just like Papa doesn't.
And I thought you didn't love me, either.
But of course I love you!
Emilia, I'm doing all this for you.
So go test your wings
and protect Mama's kingdom.
[chuckles] Yes.
[suspenseful music playing]
Hmph! Now, it's my time to shine.
Look out, Papa.
The queen is back. [laughs]
Love it!
[moans]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Lily] I have a spy within
Red Dragon's organization.
We can keep track of their every move.
[Romulo] Once I prove that
Torillo's a spy, I'll kill him.
[Emilia] I'll be taking her
place while she's away.
[Noel] If we catch the Big Four
and Emilia Ardiente…
it will be our biggest arrest.
I'd rather die than kneel before you.
[Emilia]I know I can do this
and I know what I'm doing!
[Mercedes] We're cut from the
same cloth, Lily Cruz.
Are you going to join my group…
or do you want to play second
fiddle to Emilia forever?
[theme music playing]